Register of the President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership (1931: Washington, D.C.) Records, 1931-1932 XX396
Hoover Institution Archives
- Committees File, 1927-1933.
  - Fact finding committees
    - Housing and the Community Committee
      - List of committee members (Folder 16)
      - Memoranda (Folder 17)
      - Minutes of meetings, 1931
        - October 3 (Folder 18)
        - October 31 (Folder 19)
      - Regional survey of New York and its environs (Folder 20)
      - Reports
        - On effect of housing conditions upon the efficiency of industrial workers, 1931 November 16 (Folder 21)
        - Stenographic, 1931 December 2-5 (Folder 22)
    - Industrial Decentralization and Housing Committee
      - General (Folder 23)
      - Correspondence
        - Cramer, Stuart W. (Folder 24)
        - Gries, John M. (Folder 25)
        - Haig, Robert Murray (Folder 26)
        - Leukhardt, J. C. (Folder 27)
        - Miscellaneous (Folder 28)
      - Lists
        - Acceptances and declinations (Folder 29)
        - Invitations sent (Folder 30)
        - Members (Folder 31)
        - Suggested members (Folder 32)
      - Memoranda (Folder 33)
      - Minutes of meeting, 1931 August 24-25 (Folder 34)
      - Questionnaire (Folder 35)
      - Statement on industrial decentralization in appointment of Rural Aid Board, 1931 August 20 (Folder 36)
      - Stenographer's report, 1931 December 4 (Folder 37)
    - Kitchens and Other Work Centers Committee (Box 29)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Checklist to assist in determining need for reconstructioning or modernizing (Folder 2)
      - Correspondence
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Halbert, Blanche (Folder 4)
        - Marlatt, Abby L. (Folder 5)
        - Stanley, Louise (Folder 6)
        - Wichers, H. E. (Folder 7)
      - Invoices (Folder 8)
      - Memoranda (Folder 9)
      - Reports
        - Progress (Folder 10)
        - Stenographic (Folder 11)
    - Landscape Planning and Planting Committee
      - General (Folder 12)
      - Agenda for the first meeting, 1931 June 5-6. Includes list of committee members (Folder 13)
      - Correspondence
        - Morgan, Junius S. (Folder 14)
        - Miscellaneous (Folder 15)
      - Lists
        - Books (Folder 16)
        - Possible members (Folder 17)
        - Subcommittees (Folder 18)
      - Memoranda (Folder 19)
      - Mimeographed material (Folder 20-21)
      - Regional planning notes (County of Los Angeles) (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Restrictions by subcommittee on streets, parkways, highways, and byways (Folder 2)
      - Stenographer's report, 1931 December 2-5 (Folder 3)
      - Summary of activities (Folder 4)
    - Large Scale Operations Committee
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Acknowledgments (Folder 6)
      - Correspondence. Mostly of Alfred K. Stern, Chairman (Folder 7)
      - Financial records (Folder 8)
      - Lists of committee members (Folder 9)
      - Memoranda (Folder 10)
      - Minutes of meetings
        - Undated. Includes general correspondence (Folder 11)
        - 1931 September 23 (Chicago) (Folder 12)
        - 1931 September 30 (joint) (Folder 13)
        - 1931 October 12 (Cleveland) (Folder 14)
      - Regional survey of New York and its environs (Folder 15)
      - Reports
        - General. Endorsements, 1931 November (Folder 16)
        - Final (Folder 17)
        - Stenographic, 1931 December 3 (Folder 18)
      - Statement of Alfred Stern, Chairman and Director of the Julius Rosenwald Fund (Folder 19)
      - Suggestions for committee agenda (Folder 20)
    - Negro Housing Committee
      - General (Folder 21)
      - Correspondence (Box 31)
        - Burroughs, Nannie H., Chairman (Folder 1)
        - Committee members (Folder 2)
      - Editorial file (Folder 3)
      - Invoices (Folder 4)
      - Lists
        - Members (Folder 5)
        - Negro newspapers, magazines, trade journals, and press services in the United States, 1931 October (Folder 6)
      - Material regarding copyright (Folder 7)
      - Memoranda (Folder 8)
      - Messages
        - Sent by President Herbert Hoover to the Committee, 1931 April 24 (Folder 9)
        - Suggested by Dr. James Ford to the National Negro Insurance Association, 1931 April 21 (Folder 10)
      - Publicity file (Folder 11)
      - Questionnaire (Folder 12)
      - Reports (Box 32)
        - General
          - 1931 December 2-5 (stenographic) (Folder 1)
          - 1932 (Folder 2)
        - Negro housing, 1931. Includes also endorsement and extracts of the report (Folder 3)
        - Rural, 1931 (Folder 4)
      - Statements to the committee
        - By Herbert Hoover, 1931 April 24 (Folder 5)
        - By Robert Lamont (Folder 6)
      - Studies
        - Comparative study of houses occupied by whites and Negroes in parallel areas, 1931 (Folder 7)
        - Short study of housing and ownership in Boley Community (Folder 8)
    - Reconditioning, Remodeling, Modernizing Committee
      - General (Folder 9)
      - Correspondence. Mostly of Frederick Feiker, Chairman (Folder 10)
      - Editorial file. Includes letters, memoranda, printed report (Folder 11)
      - Invoices (Folder 12)
      - List of committee members (Folder 13)
      - Memoranda. Includes press memoranda (Folder 14)
      - Minutes of meeting, 1931 May 25 (Folder 15)
      - Program of business cooperation (Folder 16)
      - Reports
        - General
          - 1931
            - General (Folder 17)
            - December 2-5 (stenographer's) (Folder 18)
          - 1932
            - June 10 (Folder 19)
            - July 26 (Folder 20)
        - Activities, 1932 (Folder 21)
        - Upkeep and improvement of the home (Folder 22)
      - Suggestions for remodeling and home modernizing, 1931 (Folder 23)
      - Tentative operating manual for conducting a local modernizing campaign, 1932 September (Folder 24)
    - Relationship of Income and the Home Committee
      - General (Folder 25)
      - Chart on cost of living (Folder 26)
      - Correspondence
        - General (Folder 27)
        - Carpenter, Niles, Chairman (Box 33, Folder 1)
        - Committee members (Folder 2)
      - Data regarding rental and sale costs of houses (Richmond, Va), 1931 (Folder 3)
      - Descriptive leaflet (Folder 4)
      - Invoices (Folder 5)
      - Letter of instructions to collecting agents (Folder 6)
      - List of committee members (Folder 7)
      - Memoranda (Folder 8)
      - Minutes of meeting, 1931 July 6 (Folder 9)
      - Press release, 1931 December 4 (Folder 10)
      - Primary research project (Folder 11)
      - Questionnaire (Folder 12)
    - Relationship of Income and the Home Committee
      - Reports
        - General
          - 1931 December 3 (tentative) (Folder 13)
          - 1931 December 4 (Folder 14)
        - Stenographic, 1931 December 2-5 (Folder 15)
      - Studies
        - Buffalo, NY
          - General (Folder 16)
          - Ten home purchasing families (Folder 17)
        - Relationship of income and home (Folder 18)
        - Two hundred families of small wage earners, Newark, NJ, 1931 (Folder 19)
      - Tentative outline of subject-matter of committee on relationship of income and home (Folder 20)
    - Subdivision Layout Committee (Box 34)
      - Correspondence (Folder 1)
      - Invoices (Folder 2)
      - List of committee members (Folder 3)
      - Memorandum (Folder 4)
      - Minutes of meeting, 1931
        - April 30 (Folder 5)
        - June 1 (Folder 6)
      - References of possible interest to committee (Folder 7)
      - Stenographer's report, 1931 December 2-5
        - General (Folder 8)
        - Endorsement (Folder 9)
        - Preliminary draft (Folder 10)
    - Taxation Committee
      - General (Folder 11)
      - Correspondence (Folder 12)
      - Financial records
        - General, regarding Bill H.R. 7620 (Folder 13)
        - Invoices (Folder 14)
      - Lists of committee members (Folder 15)
      - Memoranda (Folder 16)
      - Minutes of meetings, 1931
        - July 15 (Folder 17)
        - October 5 (Folder 18)
      - News release (Folder 19)
      - Reports
        - Preliminary report (by Marion McKay), 1931 (Folder 20)
        - First draft of report for the committee (by Richard Ely), 1931 (Folder 21)
        - Draft of report of the committee (submitted by H. L. Lutz), 1931 (Folder 22)
        - Draft of the final report, 1931. Includes endorsement of report (Folder 23)
        - Stenographer's, 1931 December 2-5 (Folder 24)
    - Types of Dwellings Committee (Box 35)
      - General
        - General (Folder 1)
        - Scope sheets (Folder 2)
      - Correspondence. Mostly of John Ihlder (Folder 3)
      - Invoices (Folder 4)
      - Lists of committee members (Folder 5)
      - Memoranda (Folder 6)
      - Minutes of meetings, 1931
        - May 4 (Folder 7)
        - June 3 (Folder 8)
        - July 17 (Folder 9)
        - September 21 (Folder 10)
        - October 17 (Folder 11)
      - Reports
        - General. Written by Robert Whitten as chapter II of the report "Neighborhoods of Small Homes: Economic Density of Low-Cost Housing in America and England," 1931 May 27 (Folder 12)
        - Stenographic, 1931 December 2-5. Includes endorsements of report (Folder 13)
        - Tentative, 1931 August 4 (Folder 14)
    - Utilities for HousesCommittee (Box 36)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Correspondence (Folder 2)
      - Invoices (Folder 3)
      - Lists of committee members (Folder 4)
      - Memoranda. Includes memoranda of meetings (Folder 5)
      - Notes on certain topics assigned for preliminary discussion to T. H. Wiggin (Folder 6)
      - Preliminary draft of a discussion on housing in unincorporated areas adjustment to cities, 1931 September 21 (Folder 7)
      - Reports
        - Draft report of the Committee, 1931 September 8 (Folder 8)
        - Forstall, Walton 1931
          - February 25 (Folder 9)
          - March 3 (Folder 10)
          - March 11 (Folder 11)
        - Stenographer's, 1931 December 2-5. Includes endorsements of report (Folder 12)
  - Correlating committees
    - Education and Service Committee
      - Correspondence
        - Ford, James M. (Folder 13)
        - Gries, John (Folder 14)
        - Hart, Joseph (Folder 15)
        - Lamont, R. P. (Folder 16)
        - Shaw, Albert (Folder 17)
      - Financial records (Folder 18)
      - Lists
        - Committee members (Folder 19)
        - Subcommittees (Folder 20)
      - Memoranda (Folder 21)
      - Reports
        - On order of business (Folder 22)
        - Stenographer's, 1931 December 2-5 (Folder 23)
    - Legislation and Administration Committee
      - General (Folder 24)
      - Financial records (Folder 25)
      - Correspondence. Mostly of Bernard J. Newman, Chairman (Folder 26)
      - List of committee members (Folder 27)
      - Memoranda (Folder 28)
      - Minutes of meetings of the committee's correlation group C, 1931
        - August 12 (Folder 29)
        - October 15 (Folder 30)
        - November 2 (Folder 31)
      - Stenographer's report, 1931 December 2-5 (Folder 32)
    - Organization Programs, Local and National Committee (Box 37)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Correspondence. Mostly of Harlean James, Chairman (Folder 2)
      - Invoices (Folder 3)
      - List of committee members (Folder 4)
      - Memoranda (Folder 5)
      - Minutes of meeting, 1932 August 14 (Folder 6)
      - Reports of the committee (Folder 7)
    - Research Committee
      - General (Folder 8)
      - Bibliographies
        - Building and housing, 1931 May 1 (Folder 9)
        - Crime and housing, 1931 June (Folder 10)
        - Housing and health, 1931 June (Folder 11)
        - Miscellany (Folder 12)
      - Correspondence
        - General (Folder 13)
        - Ford, James, Chairman (Folder 14)
      - Editorial file (Folder 15)
      - Invoices (Folder 16)
      - Lists
        - Committee members (Folder 17)
        - Suggestions for research (Folder 18)
      - Memoranda (Folder 19)
      - Minutes of meetings, 1931
        - September 11 (Folder 20)
        - October 9 (Folder 21)
      - Press release, 1931 December 5 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Real estate activity chart, 1932 (Folder 2)
      - Reports
        - General, 1931
          - October-November. Includes preliminary draft of report (Folder 3)
          - December 5 (Folder 4)
        - Committee secretaries, 1931 September 9 (Folder 5)
        - Stenographer, 1931 December 2-5. Includes endorsement of report (Folder 6)
      - Research projects
        - General. Includes research memorandum outline, 1931 October 9 (Folder 7)
        - Home economics, 1931-1932 (Folder 8)
        - Post conference (Folder 9)
      - Reviews of the work by other committees
        - Design Committee, 1931 November 3 (Folder 10)
        - Reconditioning, Remodeling and Modernizing Committee, 1931 November 1 (Folder 11)
        - Study in home ownership and leasing (Folder 12)
    - Standards and Objectives Committee
      - General (Folder 13)
      - Correspondence (Folder 14)
      - Issue of Housing, 1931 October (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Lists
        - Committee members (Folder 2)
        - Personnel (Folder 3)
      - Memoranda (Folder 4)
      - Minutes of meetings, 1931
        - September 25 (Folder 5)
        - October 12-13 (Folder 6)
        - October 28-29 (Folder 7)
      - Statement of Wilson Compton, 1932 (Folder 8)
      - Stenographer's report, 1931 December 2-5
        - General (Folder 9)
        - Endorsement of report (Folder 10)
        - Index to the report (Folder 11)
        - Proposed changes (Folder 12)
    - Technological Development Committee
      - General (Folder 13)
      - Appendices and bibliographies (Folder 14)
      - Correspondence (Folder 15)
      - Invoices (Folder 16)
      - List of committee members (Folder 17)
      - Memoranda (Folder 18)
      - Minutes of meetings, 1931
        - July 31 (Folder 19)
        - September 18 (Folder 20)
      - Reports
        - Stenographic, 1931 December 2-5 (Folder 21)
        - Tentative
          - Draft. Includes comments on report, 1931 October-November (Folder 22)
          - Review of tentative report, 1931 December (Folder 23)
      - Tentative program, 1931 July 30 (Folder 24)
- Reports, 1930-1934.
  Correspondence, memoranda, typescripts of introductions, galleys, lists, and reviews, related to the eleven volumes put out by the Conference, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - General. Includes correspondence, memoranda, typescripts of introductions, galleys (Box 40)
    - Vol. 1 and 5 (Folder 1)
    - Vol. 7 (Folder 2)
    - Vol. 9 (Folder 3)
    - Vol. 11 (Folder 4)
  - Commendatory remarks (Folder 5)
  - Correspondence
    - Committee reports
    - General (Folder 6-7)
      - Committee secretaries (Folder 8)
    - Complimentary copies
      - General (Folder 9)
      - Index (Folder 10)
      - Reprints (Folder 11)
      - Volume 1. Planning for Residential Districts (Folder 12)
      - Volume 2. Home Finance and Taxation (Folder 13)
      - Volume 3. Slums, Large-Scale Housing and Decentralization (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Volume 4. Home Ownership, Income and Types of Dwellings (Folder 2)
      - Volume 5. House design, Construction and Equipment (Folder 3)
      - Volume 6. Negro Housing (Folder 4)
      - Volume 7. Farm and Village Housing (Folder 5)
      - Volume 8. Housing and the Community; Home Repair and Remodeling (Folder 6)
      - Volume 9. Household Management and Kitchens (Folder 7)
      - Volume 10. Homemaking, Home Furnishing and Information Services (Folder 8)
      - Vol. 11. Housing Objectives and Programs (Folder 9)
    - Planning Committee set (Folder 10)
  - Forewords
    - Lamont, Robert (vol. 4) (Folder 11)
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman (vol. 7) (Folder 12)
  - List of possible titles. Includes correspondence (Folder 13)
  - Memoranda re distribution of Conference volumes (Folder 14)
  - Requests for complimentary copies of volumes (Folder 15)
  - Reviews (Box 42)
    - General
      - General (Folder 1-2)
      - Vol. 1-11 (Folder 3)
      - Vol. 7 (Folder 4)
    - Index of reviews
      - By magazine (Folder 5-7)
      - By magazine (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - By volume (Folder 2)
  - Subject file
    - Circularizationa of the volumes (Folder 3-4)
    - Sales of conference volumes (Folder 5)
- Publicity File, 1922-1947.
  Articles, broadcasts, clippings, correspondence, press releases, programs, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - General. Includes pre-conference material (Box 43, Folder 6-7)
  - Articles
    - Bricklayer, Mason and Plasterer, 1930 September (Folder 8)
    - United States Daily (on the President's Conference), 1932-1933 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Washington Herald, 1930 September 9 (Folder 2)
  - Broadcasts (Folder 3)
  - Clippings
    - General (Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook of reviews on all conference volumes (Folder 5)
    - Supplement to scrapbook of reviews (Box 44A., Folder 6)
  - Correspondence regarding copyright issues (Box 45, Folder 1-4)
  - Editorial file (Box 46)
    - General (Folder 1)
    - Bibliography (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - General
          - Vol. 1 (Folder 3)
          - Vol. 2 (Folder 4)
          - Vol. 3 (Folder 5)
          - Vol. 4 (Folder 6)
          - Vol. 5 (Folder 7)
          - Vol. 6 (Folder 8)
          - Vol. 7 (Folder 9)
          - Vol. 8 (Folder 10)
          - Vol. 9 (Folder 11)
          - Vol. 10 (Folder 12)
          - Vol. 11 (Box 47, Folder 1)
        - Correlative volume (Folder 2)
        - Vol. 2, second edition (Folder 3)
        - Vol. 8, second edition (Folder 4)
      - Publications (Folder 5)
    - Index (Folder 6)
  - Press releases
    - By committee (Folder 7)
    - By date (Folder 8-9)
    - By volume (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Press releases (duplicate set) (Folder 3-4)
  - Programs of conferences, conventions and sessions, 1930-1931 (Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 6)
- Subject File, 1926-1933.
  Correspondence, clippings, lists, memoranda, minutes of meetings, press releases, printed matter, reports, arranged alphabetically by name of organization affiliated with the Conference
  - General. Mostly national organizations (Box 48)
    - Ac-B (Folder 7)
    - Al-Am (Folder 8)
    - Am (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Ar-As (Folder 2)
    - B (Folder 3)
    - C (Folder 4)
    - D-L (Folder 5)
    - E (Folder 6)
    - G (Folder 7)
    - F (Folder 8)
    - H (Folder 9)
    - I (Folder 10)
    - L (Folder 11)
    - M (Folder 12)
    - M-Z (Folder 13)
    - Ne-z (Folder 14)
    - O (Folder 15)
    - P (Folder 16)
    - S (Folder 17)
    - T (Folder 18)
    - U (Folder 19)
    - W (Folder 20)
  - Committee for Economic and Social Progress (Folder 21)
  - Committee for Economic Recovery (Folder 22)
  - Home Loan Bank (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research (Folder 2)
  - National Conference of Business and Industrial Committees (Folder 3)
  - National Conference on Construction (Folder 4)
  - National Conference on Street and Highway Safety (Folder 5)
  - Reconstruction Finance Corporation (Folder 6)
  - Renovize Philadelphia Campaign (Folder 7)
  - United States. Department of Commerce (Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 9)
- Oversize Material.
  Ledgers
- Photograph, 1931 December 2 (Folder Map case)
  One photograph depicting the opening session of the Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership (m*A)